Andrei Trifu

Contact

Phone 07963380620

Email

andrei.trifu84@gmail.com

LinkedIn

GitHub

Portfolio

Professional qualifications

2021

AWS Certified Solutions Architect

Amazon Web Services

2017

STCW Seafarer Safety Training

International Maritime Organisation

Education

2023

Fullstack Software Developer Bootcamp

iO Academy

2012-2016

Deck Officer

Constanta Naval Academy

2007-2009

Masters of Science in Quality Management

Bucharest Academy of Economic Studies

2003-2007

Bachelor of Arts in Economic Studies

Bucharest Academy of Economic Studies

About me

I'm an enthusiastic full-stack developer with a strong focus on back-end technologies. In my spare time, I like to go on long nature walks with my friends, go to the cinema, or play badminton at my local club. I have always had a passion for technology which drives me to stay updated on the latest industry trends and best practices.

Projects

I recently studied software development at iO Academy and during my time there I worked on a range of projects, both individually and in a scrum team. Below is a small selection of my favourites:

Q React virtual library

We had to create a communal bookshelf website using React and Tailwind, on which users can see all the available books, claim, return or review a title. It came with the option to add a new book to the system and also search and filter the books by title, author or genre.

O Portfolio website

Using JavaScript and Tailwind I've created a website that contains a brief description of myself and that has links to a few of my projects.

Job history

February 2018 - present
O Johnson Matthey Fuel Cells

Research and development technician

As a senior technician, I had to oversee the training of new team members consisting of 12 Junior technicians on quality control issues, fostering a culture of continuous improvement. I collaborated with the process engineers to identify and implement measures to improve the quality of the fuel cells produced. I had to write comprehensive documentation for quality and process issues and a description of the corrective actions taken to resolve them.

June 2010 - January 2018

O Liliput Co

Store Manager

As an organic food store manager, I've established and nurtured strong customer relationships by consistently delivering exceptional service and support, resulting in a customer satisfaction rate of over 95% and a significant increase in repeat business. I've efficiently managed store operations, including inventory control, product selection, and customer service initiatives. I've also developed and implemented marketing strategies to promote organic products and increase store visibility in the community.

September 2009 - June 2010

Horeca Expert

Sales representative

As a sales representative for a large hotel and restaurant equipment supply company, I had to utilize a consultative approach to help customers identify and procure essential hospitality products, delivering exceptional service throughout the process.